affinnova.com 2016-11-02

# Privacy Policy - Affinnova

_Last Updated: August, 2014_

This privacy policy (“Privacy Policy”) discloses the information that Affinnova, Inc. (“Affinnova”) gathers on www.affinnova.com and in the Affinnova Integrated Platform (the “Sites”), as well as ways in which Affinnova processes and sometimes shares such information.

Except where otherwise expressly indicated in this Privacy Policy or on the Sites, this Privacy Policy applies only to information collected on the Sites and does not apply to information collected outside of the Sites. Before using or submitting information to the Sites, please review this Privacy Policy carefully.

Certain areas of the Sites contain information, content or services intended only for users who are registered to use them (“Registered Users”), and Affinnova reserves the right to limit those areas to Registered Users. This Privacy Policy addresses Affinnova’s privacy practices relating to general use of the Sites, as well as use of the Sites by Registered Users.

  1. **Information Affinnova Collects **  
Affinnova collects the following types of information from users of the Sites:
    1. **Personally Identifiable Information**  
Affinnova may receive and store any information that you enter on the Sites or provide to Affinnova in any other way on or through the Sites that would allow Affinnova to identify you or contact you (collectively “Personally Identifiable Information”). The Personally Identifiable Information that you provide will be used by Affinnova only in accordance with this Privacy Policy. Examples of Personally Identifiable Information that Affinnova may collect from you are: 
      * Your name, email address, telephone number, employer’s industry, name and address and job title if you are a Registered User or are otherwise asked to provide such information, such as information you provide in connection with your request to view a demonstration of our products and services;
      * The names and email addresses of those who communicate with Affinnova by email;
      * Email addresses of any person that you provide in connection with your use of certain features of the Sites; and
      * Information you provide about yourself when you apply for employment via the Sites.

You may choose not to provide Affinnova with certain Personally Identifiable Information but then you may not be able to take advantage of certain features of the Sites.

    2. **Automatic Information**  
Affinnova may receive and store certain types of technical information whenever you interact with Affinnova through the Sites. We may automatically receive and record your browser information, operating system information, IP address, the page you requested and the page the directed you to the Sites. This allows Affinnova to enhance your experience and better support your needs. This information is not stored in a manner that is personally identifiable with you and may include the following: 
      1. _Aggregate Information_  
In connection with your visit to the Sites, Affinnova may automatically collect usage information, such as the numbers of users and frequency of use. With respect to the Affinnova Integrated Platform, Affinnova may automatically collect certain statistical information, including your last sign-on, number of concepts, number of dynamic elements, and number of image objects, number of text objects per concept and word count. This data is only used in the aggregate as a statistical measure and not in a manner that would identify you personally. Aggregate information generally is collected through the use of “cookies” as discussed below.
      2. _Cookies_  
Affinnova uses “cookies” to help you access and navigate the Sites more efficiently and to statistically monitor how many people are using the Sites. A “cookie” is a small file or tool stored on your hard drive containing information that allows Affinnova to deliver customized information to you. If you become a Registered User, Affinnova may use cookies to store your email address, password and other technical information related to the Sites so that Affinnova can identify you when you return to the Sites, track your use of the Sites and customize the Sites for you. You may set your browser to notify you of or decline the receipt of cookies. Certain features of the Sites may not, however, function properly or be available if your browser is configured to disable cookies. Affinnova uses both “session” and “persistent” cookies on the Sites. Session cookies are temporary bits of information that are erased once you exit your Web browser or turn off your computer. Persistent cookies are more permanent bits of information that are placed on the hard drive of your computer and stay there unless you delete the cookie. Persistent cookies store information on your computer for a number of reasons, such as retrieving certain information you have previously provided (i.e., email address and password) and helping to determine what areas of the Sites you find most valuable. Many companies offer programs that help you to visit websites anonymously and Affinnova wants you to be aware that these programs are available, but use of such programs may block your access to certain features of the Sites.
      3. _Email Communications_  
When you send an email to Affinnova, either through the “Contact” tab on the Sites or otherwise, Affinnova may retain your e-mail address and the contents of the email that you send. This Privacy Policy does not apply to content, business information, ideas, concepts or inventions that you send to Affinnova by email. Please refer to Affinnova’s terms and conditions of use applicable to the services that you are using for Affinnova’s policy with respect to such information. If you want to keep the information in your email(s) private or proprietary, please do not send such information in an email to Affinnova.
    3. **How Affinnova Uses Information **  
When you provide Affinnova with your Personally Identifiable Information, Affinnova may use it to manage Affinnova’s registry of Registered Users, facilitate communication between Affinnova and you and/or provide you with other information Affinnova feels may be of interest to you. Affinnova also uses information collected to customize, analyze, adjust and improve the Sites to meet Affinnova’s users’ needs. Affinnova also may use the information to enforce Affinnova’s agreements with you, to prevent fraud and other prohibited or illegal activities and for other legally permissible purposes. These uses of your Personally Identifiable Information may include, without limitation, the following:
      1. **Public Areas**  
Personally Identifiable Information collected in public areas of the Sites is used solely for the purpose for which it is collected. For example, Personally Identifiable Information provided in connection with your request for a demonstration of our products and services is used solely to contact you about a demonstration; likewise, Personally Identifiable Information that you submit to the Sites in connection with your interest in the Affinnova employment opportunities described on the Sites is used solely to consider you for such employment opportunities.
      2. **Registered User Areas**  
Certain areas of the Sites are accessible only to Registered Users (“Registered User Areas”). Information that you make available in or through a Registered User Area may be viewed, accessed or collected by, or disclosed to, other Registered Users that you invite to view such information and may be used by such other Registered Users in ways neither you nor Affinnova are able to control or predict, including, without limitation, disclosure of your information to the public or to contact you for unauthorized purposes.  
Affinnova may use the Personally Identifiable Information that you provide when registering to become a Registered User to send you information about Registered User benefits, features included in the Registered User Areas and other information that Affinnova believes is relevant and useful to its Registered Users. Affinnova does not sell mailing lists (names and mailing addresses) and email addresses of Registered Users to third parties.
      3. **Aggregate Information**  
The aggregate information collected by Affinnova is used to create profiles of the audience for the Sites that include anonymous statistical demographic information but no Personally Identifiable Information. This aggregate information is used to, among other things, determine trends and needs and enhance the Sites for users.
      4. **Emails and Newsletters**  
From time to time, Affinnova may use your Personally Identifiable Information to send you important administrative information regarding the Sites and related services or changes to Affinnova’s Terms of Use or other applicable terms and policies. Affinnova also may use your Personally Identifiable Information to send you periodic emails and newsletters with information on new products and services, updates to the Sites or upcoming events. You may at any time “opt out” of having your Personally Identifiable Information as part of Affinnova’s marketing mailing list or otherwise (see “Opting Out” in Section D. below).
****
****
    4. With Whom Affinnova Shares Information  
Affinnova will not give, share, sell or trade your Personally Identifiable Information to or with any third parties in any way, other than under the following circumstances: 
      1. **Third-Party Service Providers**  
Affinnova may retain other companies and individuals to perform functions on Affinnova’s behalf. Affinnova may share your Personally Identifiable Information with such third-party service providers to perform these functions consistent with this Privacy Policy. Examples include Web hosting companies, data analysis firms and email service providers.
      2. **Compliance with Law and Fraud Protection**  
Affinnova may disclose any information, including without limitation Personally Identifiable Information, that Affinnova deems necessary, in its sole discretion and without your prior permission, to comply with any applicable law, regulation, legal process or governmental request. Affinnova also may exchange information, including without limitation Personally Identifiable Information, with other companies and organizations for credit fraud protection, risk reduction and related activities or to protect the rights, property of safety of Affinnova and its agents, employees or affiliates or others. Affinnova reserves the right to disclose a user’s Personally Identifiable Information if Affinnova believes the user is in violation of Affinnova’s Terms of Use, even without a subpoena, warrant or other court order.
      3. **Sale or Transfer of Information**  
In the event of a sale, merger, liquidation, dissolution or sale or transfer of substantially all of the assets of Affinnova or the Sites, Personally Identifiable Information and/or other information collected about you via the Sites may be sold, assigned or transferred to Affinnova’s lender(s) or prospective acquirer(s), as well as the party acquiring all or substantially all of the equity and/or assets of Affinnova or any of the Sites, in order to permit the party to continue the operation of the applicable Site or service, including the Registered User Areas. By using the Sites, you consent to the sale and transfer of your information as described in this paragraph.
    5. **Important Disclosures, Practices and Contact Information**
      1. **Accessing, Updating or Deleting your Personally Identifiable Information**  
If you are a Registered User and would like to review, update or delete your registration information, please contact us at info@affinnova.com. 
      2. **Opting Out**  
Affinnova respects the privacy of your Personally Identifiable Information. If you tell Affinnova that you do not wish to have this information used as a basis for further contact with you, Affinnova will respect your wishes. You also may choose not to provide Affinnova with certain information, but that may result in your inability to use certain features of the Sites. You may instruct Affinnova to stop sending you materials (e.g., email messages, newsletters) by sending an email with your email address and your opt-out instructions to info@affinnova.com or, if available, following the unsubscribe instructions provided in those materials. Affinnova may, however, continue to contact you to provide service to your account. Please note that if you use more than one name or email address when communicating with Affinnova or participating on the Sites, you may continue to receive communications from Affinnova to any name and/or email address which you have not specified in your opt-out request.

Affinnova provides you with the following options for removing your Personally Identifiable Information from Affinnova’s database for marketing purposes:

        1. You can send an email to info@affinnova.com; or 2. You can send mail to Affinnova, Inc., 265 Winter Street, Waltham, MA 02451.
      3. **Third Party Links**  
The Sites may contain links to third-party websites. Please be aware that Affinnova cannot control and is not responsible for the information collection practices of such websites, which may differ from those of Affinnova. Affinnova encourages you to review and understand the privacy policies of these websites before providing any information to them.
      4. **Data Security**  
Affinnova maintains a variety of commercially reasonable physical, electronic and procedural safeguards designed to protect your Personally Identifiable Information from unauthorized access and disclosure. For example, Affinnova uses accepted tools and techniques to protect against unauthorized access to Affinnova’s systems. You should be aware that Affinnova has no control over the security of other websites on the Internet that you might visit or with which you might interact even when a link may appear to another site from the Sites. Although Affinnova takes steps to secure your information, Affinnova does not promise, and you should not expect, that your personal information, searches or other communications would always remain secure. In the event of a breach of the confidentiality or security of your information, including your Personally Identifiable Information, Affinnova will notify you as necessary and if possible so that you can take appropriate protective steps. Affinnova may notify you under such circumstances using the email address(es) that Affinnova has on record for you and/or by regular mail (if available).
      5. **Children**  
Each of the Sites is a general audience site and is not intended for children under 13. Affinnova requires that only persons 13 years of age or older use the Sites. By using any of the Sites, you hereby represent that you are at least 13 years old. Affinnova does not knowingly market to, solicit information, accept service or collect information from children under the age of 13. When any of the Sites has actual knowledge that it collects information from children or offers a service directed toward children, it will comply with applicable laws, including the U.S. Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act.
      6. **Changes to this Privacy Policy**  
At any time without prior notice, Affinnova may update this Privacy Policy to reflect changes in Affinnova’s practices. When Affinnova posts changes to this Privacy Policy, Affinnova will revise the “Last Updated” date at the top of this page. If Affinnova makes any material change to this Privacy Policy, Affinnova will notify each Registered User by sending an email to the email address provided to Affinnova in a Registered User’s account, profile and/or registration and/or by prominently posting notice of the changes on the Sites. Affinnova will offer you the opportunity to opt-out of any materially changed Privacy Policy. Affinnova encourages you to ‘bookmark’ this Privacy Policy and to periodically review it to inform yourself of changes to it or any of Affinnova’s other policies. Any changes to Affinnova’s Privacy Policy will become effective upon Affinnova’s posting of the updated policy. Use of any of the Sites constitutes your acceptance of the terms of this Privacy Policy then in effect.
      7. **California Privacy Rights Under California Civil Code Section 1798.83**  
If you are a resident of California (“California Users”), in addition to the rights set forth in this Privacy Policy, you generally have the right to request information from Affinnova regarding the manner in which Affinnova shares certain categories of Personally Identifiable Information with third parties for their direct marketing purposes. Under the law, however, a business is not required to provide this information if it adopts and discloses to the public (in its privacy policy) a policy of not disclosing customer’s personal information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes unless the customer first affirmatively agrees to the disclosure, as long as the business maintains and discloses this policy. Rather, the business may comply with the law by notifying California Users of their rights to prevent disclosure of personal information and providing a cost-free means to exercise that right. As stated above, Affinnova does not share such Personally Identifiable Information with third parties for their direct marketing purposes unless you have requested Affinnova to do so or have otherwise consented and then only subject to your right to opt-out of sharing your personal information for third party marketing purposes. Please note that whenever you opt in to receive future communications from a third party, your information will be subject to the third party’s privacy policy. If you later decide that you do not want that third party to use your information, you will need to contact the third party directly, as Affinnova has no control over how third parties use information. You should always review the privacy policy of any party that collects your information to determine how it will handle your information. Please note that Affinnova is only required to respond to one request per user per year. Affinnova is not required to respond to requests made by means other than through info@affinnova.com.
      8. **Users From Outside the United States**  
By visiting the Sites, submitting information or using any of Affinnova’s products or services, you acknowledge that you accept the practices and policies outlined in this Privacy Policy and consent to having your data transferred to and processed in the United States. If you do not agree to this Privacy Policy, please do not use any of the Sites.
      9. **No Rights of Third Parties**  
This Privacy Policy does not create rights enforceable by third parties.
      10. **Contacting Affinnova**  
If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, the practices of any of the Sites or your dealings with us, please feel free to contact Affinnova at: 

Affinnova, Inc. 265 Winter Street Waltham, MA 02451 Tel: 781.464.4700 Fax: 781.464.4702 Email:info@affinnova.com

****************
